MALISSA ADAMS

DELEXPERT

CONTACT

612.730.3103

madams@stantonadams.com

www.stantonadams.com

Minneapolis MN

SKILLS

Leadership Development

Team Building

Training

Public Speaking

EDUCATION

Master of Non-Profit & Public Admin

Metropolitan State University

2017-2020

Bachelor's Degree, Business Mgmnt

Rasmussen University

2014-2016

Certified Full Stack Developer

University of Minnesota

2021-2022

CODING LANGUAGES

HTML



JavaScript

PROFILE

Malissa Stanton Adams is an accomplished executive with over 14 years of experience in the field of diversity and inclusion, non-profit management, and public administration. Malissa has a proven track record of delivering exceptional results in a variety of leadership roles, including Executive Director, Director of People & Operations, Program Manager, and Operations Manager. She holds an MBA in Non-Profit & Public Administration from Metro State University and a Bachelor's Degree in Business Management from Rasmussen University.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Executive Director

The Diversity Institute

2013-- Present

I engage with a wide array of stakeholders to help set and execute a vision that elevates the Diversityprofession and improves outcomes for marginalized communities. Provide consulting, coaching, andtraining services to Executive Leaders, Chief Diversity Officers, and staff in public, private, nonprofit, and educational institutions on successful Inclusion program strategies and ERG implementation withan integrated approach that fully realizes the business case. Developed, socialized, implemented, andmanaged the strategy for small to midsized businesses. Providing rigor and structure around InclusionRecruiting, DEI Program Development, Talent Pipeline Development, and Storytelling. Help client-led

teams focus on pipelining diverse talent across organization lines of businesses while collaborating with the Recruiting team to embed the Inclusion Recruiting strategy into sourcing, interviewing, selection, and onboarding processes while supporting the development of diversity-focused training.

Many of our clients know that Diversity is essential; they're just not sure where to start.

Director of People and Operations

Genesys Works

2022-2023

The People Operations Director embodies Gensys Works culture and core values by cultivating a great team member experience and is a champion for both team members and their leaders. I am responsible for providing a people business partnership that results in an engaged workforce and a more productive business. I am also responsible for and contribute to developing people strategies, overseeing a team of People Operations Business Partner's (POBP's) and, provide thought leadership to the organization and the senior leadership teams developing, and executing talent management and change management strategies while partnering with the Centers of Excellence (Talent Management, Employee Relations, Recruiting, Total Rewards, etc.) to deliver results against the people strategies.

Responsibilities:

- Provide thought leadership and consultation/support on people and organizational issues: collectively, directly and through matrix management throughout the organization, leveraging resources, programs and tools to achieve desired outcomes.
- Actively participate with and influence the leadership team, advising on people and organization impact of business plans and decisions; ensure that change and transformation plans are established and effectively executed.
- Identify and implement strategies which improve employee engagement year over year, as measured through the company's engagement survey.
- Analyze HR metrics to identify business opportunities working with leadership to develop and implement solutions.
- Drive talent management and succession planning activities within the business.



MALISSA ADAMS

DELEXPERT

CONTACT

612.730.3103

madams@stantonadams.com

www.stantonadams.com

Minneapolis MN

EXPERTISE

- My mission is to support individuals and organizations working to achieve racial equity. I enjoy working with leaders who are willing to experiment actively with innovative approaches for solving problems. I offer assistance and training for individuals, organizations, and communities in several crucial areas, including developing curricula and managing diversity initiatives in the workplace.
- I believe that each of us has the power to change ourselves, our families, our communities, our work, and our macroenvironment. But first, we must change our hearts and minds. Through my work, I am here to help others on their journey to understanding. Together we can commit to making a difference.

REFERENCES

Reference Name: Dr. Nerita Hughes

612-730-3215

nerita.hughes@gmail.com

Reference Name: Trenda Boyeum

612.220.4408

Trendabb@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Program Manager

Catholic Charities Twin Cities

2017 - 2019

- Lead and Manage-Provide leadership to manage vital aspects of success and uphold a high level of accountability for case management and specific assistance needs. Coach, mentor, and motivate employees to do their best.
- · Accountability and Evaluation-Create an environment of accountability and evaluation, by monitoring and analyzing spending, program data, staff outputs, and client outcomes to make sound decisions regarding staffing, clients, and
- Improve Processes- Continuously improve services, programs, and the department by identifying areas of growth, potential barriers, or new opportunities.
- Work to capitalize on opportunities or create solutions, and execute changes while sensitively providing staff transparency and time to process.
- · Collect and report program data, including but not limited to, HMIS reporting and funders' required data.

Rapid Rehousing Advocate

2015 - 2017

Simpson Housing Services

- Assess housing barriers of individuals experiencing homelessness to determine housing and service needs. Develop housing procurement, financial, and selfsufficiency case management plan with clients. This includes intake interview to determine client's needs, goals, and eligibility.
- Provide mediation and advocacy with landlords on the client's behalf to develop a workable plan to obtain and or maintain housing. Assist participants in locating and securing housing of their choice.
- Serve as an ongoing liaison between property managers and participants. Provide information and referral assistance regarding available support from appropriate social service agencies and/or community programs. Assist in development of and encourage adherence to a personal budget through proactive housing and budget counseling sessions; provide budget counseling and education to assist clients in establishing payments plans for bills and past debts and to assist clients in obtaining and maintaining their housing. Assist participants in development of a strength-based/solution-focused individualized goal and action plan that promotes permanent housing and self-sufficiency; develop an effective, timely referral network in order to ensure ongoing direction and support as needed. Provide pro-active follow-up home visits to ensure stability and further progress towards self-sufficiency; this includes support, advocacy, reducing isolation, listening, problem solving, and identification of resources to assist with reintegration of participants in the community. Apply knowledge of residential lease contracts to educate clients of their rights and responsibilities. Maintain accurate daily logs records, monthly outcome reports, and files for each client. Transport clients as deemed necessary. Collect and report program data, including but not limited to HMIS reporting and funders' required data.

MALISSA ADAMS

DEI EXPERT

TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

I am writing to express my interest in the Executive Director position at Minnesota's Community Action Partnership Association, as advertised on your website. With a strong background in human services, nonprofit administration, and a genuine passion for combating poverty in our communities, I believe that my skills and experiences make me an ideal candidate for this role. I am excited about the opportunity to lead the association and contribute significantly to the success of the Community Action Agencies in Minnesota.

I hold a Bachelor's Degree in Public Administration and have over four years of experience in related fields. My Master's Degree in Nonprofit Public Administration has further honed my skills and expertise in the nonprofit sector. Over the past three years, I have successfully collaborated with elected and appointed officials, as well as worked closely with the state legislature. I worked closely with the Council of Minnesotans of African Decent. Where I worked closely with state legislature Rena Moran. The experience provided me with a deep understanding of the importance of advocacy and collaboration in our work.

As an experienced nonprofit administrator, I have overseen budgets, managed teams, and developed strategies to address various challenges. My experience working with diverse communities, cultures, and income levels has equipped me with the ability to engage in constructive and courageous conversations, fostering trust and collaboration among stakeholders. I have a proven track record of interpreting and disseminating poverty research, and I possess a working knowledge of federal and state-funded programs. In previous roles, I have demonstrated my ability to think multidimensionally, combining creative problem-solving, critical thinking, and strategic thinking to drive organizational success. I have also developed and maintained a strong organizational culture based on integrity, honesty, respect, and collaboration.

Although I have not previously worked directly with Community Action Agencies, I am confident that my background in human services and public administration will allow me to quickly adapt to the unique needs and challenges of these organizations. I am eager to learn more about the work of the Minnesota Community Action Partnership Association and contribute my skills and experiences to make a meaningful impact in the lives of those facing poverty in our communities.

Thank you for considering my application for the Executive Director position. I am excited about the opportunity to further discuss how my background and qualifications align with your organization's needs. Please feel free to contact me at 612.730.3103 or madams@stantonadams.com to schedule a conversation.

SINCERELY,

MALISSA ADAMS

Malissa Adams